Wesley Jones

Software Developer

CAREER SUMMARY

Ambitious Software Developer who completed a BS in Physics and an intensive full-stack coding bootcamp. More recent experience includes working collaboratively on back-end development and working with CICD pipelines. Critical thinker with the ability to take abstract problems and find innovative and timely solutions within logical frameworks.

RELEVANT SKILLS

Languages: Java, TypeScript, JavaScript, Python, SQL Frameworks: Angular, React, Redux, Bootstrap, jQuery, Node, Express, Flask, Spring, Spring Boot, HTML, CSS, JSX

Other: API, Jest, Yarn, Git, Webpack, Tensorflow, Babel, LabVIEW, Heroku, MongoDB, Firebase, Postman, Unit Testing, TDD, MySQL, PostgreSQL, CICD, Jules, Jenkins, CloudFoundry, Gaia, Cassandra, Splunk, Tableau, AWS(cert in progress)

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

JPMorgan Chase & Co., Wilmington, DE

Feb 2020 - Present

Software Engineer

- Developed, tested, and deployed enterprise Java Spring Boot applications on an agile team
- Collaborate with teammates to break down and resolve complicated problems
- Configuring and troubleshooting CICD pipeline for multiple environments and ensuring successful deployment as well as setting up alerting and reporting to notify team when issues arise with an application
- Develop applications which send RESTful API requests and map json objects to other objects for API to consume

Photonis USA, Lancaster, PA

May 2016 - Aug 2016

Temporary Engineering Technician

Successfully translated a crucial program on a legacy system into a modern system with LabVIEW software.

EDUCATION

Zip Code Wilmington, Wilmington, DE

Oct 2019 - Jan 2020

Software Developer

- Completed over 1200 hours of software-development projects and training in an immersive program.
- Accepted into a competitive and nationally recognized educational bootcamp admitting only 8% of applicants.
- Gained experience in Java, object-oriented programming, pair coding, and Agile & Scrum methodologies.
- Developed, tested, and debugged code in addition to helping design project structure in team assignments.

Technical Projects:

- Scrabble Cheat App Solo project developed with a React frontend, and a Flask backend as well as business logic. Performs RESTful operations and is deployed on Heroku.
- Blog Web App Worked with a team of five to build a full-stack web app with a Spring Boot backend and an Angular/TS frontend. Implemented RESTful operations and deployed to cloud service. As a result of good communication and teamwork, completed objectives successfully and in a timely manner.

Millersville University of Pennsylvania, Millersville, PA

Aug 2015 - May 2019

Bachelor of Science

Major Physics, Minor Mathematics

OTHER EXPERIENCE

Spooky Nook Sports, Manheim, PA

May 2018 - April 2019

Security Officer

• Performed security checks of bags and personal items to ensure guest safety.

YMCA, Coatesville, PA Feb 2017 - Jan 2018

Lifeguard

• Worked with a team to ensure the safety of 100+ daily guests without incident.